Guide to the Bruce Baillie papers M1913
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bruce Baillie papers
1956-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Baillie, Bruce, 1931-
M1913
55 Linear Feet (72 boxes, 1 map folder)
Bruce Baillie is an American experimental filmmaker and founding member of Canyon Cinema in San Francisco. In 1961, Baillie, along with Chick Strand and others, founded San Francisco Cinematheque.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University Libraries in 2012.
Experimental films; San Francisco Cinematheque (Calif.); Canyon Cinema; Baillie, Bruce, 1931-; Baillie, Bruce, 1931-
- Series 1: Personal Papers
  - Baillie "Introduction to the Collection", 2012. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, ca. 1950s-1970s. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Drawings and Sketches, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Marriage Certificate, 1963. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, ca. 1963. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Drawing, 1964. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Interview, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Poetry Booklets, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Paper" magazines, 1966. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baillie CV and Guggenheim Statement, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Doors" concert poster, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters, Misc. Notes, and Receipts, 1969. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Texas & Rice University Papers, 1969-1970. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Texas Papers, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mendocino Notes, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Catalog and Poems, ca. 1970. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Short Pieces and Notes, 1970s. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - P-38 Papers, 1973-1976. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Misc. Notes, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Notes and Letters, 1974-1975. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Federation of the Arts, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Diary, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Martial Arts Papers, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tax Records, 1976-1977. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Bish Papers, ca. 1977. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - New York City Papers, ca. 1977. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Florida State University System Application, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Yoga School and Religious Pamphlets, ca. 1978. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chinmaya Spirtual Camp Papers, 1979-1980. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Buddhism Materials, 1979-1980. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - James Blue Tribute, 1980. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Notes, ca. 1980. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Descriptive Titles, ca. 1980. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Number 2" Folder, ca. 1980. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous News Clippings, 1980s. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Palmers Lab, 1980-1981. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1980-1981. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Radio Free Radio papers, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Descriptive Narrative, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Form Notes, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Basic Folder, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conclusion notes, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tulley News Clippings, 1984. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Poems and Notes, ca. 1984-1985. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Current Notes, 1985. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Possible Projects, ca. 1985. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Baillie Papers, ca. 1985. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Notes and Drawings, ca. 1986. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Insurance Papers and Miscellaneous, ca. 1986. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Essays and Letters, ca. 1986. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Notes and Papers, 1987. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Spiritual Flyers and Papers, 1987. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous: 1987, 1 of 2. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous: 1987, 2 of 2. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bagumbayan Journal, The Philippines, 1988-1989. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian "Air & Space" magazine, 1996. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Wall Picture, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Will and Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stained Glass Drawings and Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Drawings and Clippings, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Quixote and its Contexts" essay, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Interview, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Baillie Misc. Handwritten Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Drawings, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Memo Notebook, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten Journal Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Baillie Notebook, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - College Notebooks: 1954-1955, 1 of 3. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - College Notebooks: 1954-1955, 2 of 3. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - College Notebooks: 1954-1955, 3 of 3. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - College Papers, 1956. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - College Notebooks and Papers, 1955-1956. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - College Notebooks, 1955-1956. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - College Notebooks, 1957. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - College Notebooks, 1957-1959. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Notes, 1957-1959. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Poems, notes, and sketches, 1958-1959. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks, 1959. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks, 1960-1965. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks, 1961-1963. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1963-1964. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 1966. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, 1966-1967. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Papers and Notes, 1966-1967. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks, 1968-1969. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks, 1968-1969. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1969-1970. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1970-1971. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 1971. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, 1972. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: 1973, 1 of 3. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1973, 2 of 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1973, 3 of 3. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 1974, 1 of 2. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: 1974, 2 of 2. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: 1975, 1 of 2. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1975, 2 of 2. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1976, 1 of 2. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 1976, 2 of 2. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, 1977. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1978, 1 of 2. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1978, 2 of 2. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 1979. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, 1979-1980. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks, 1979-1980. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1980, 1 of 3. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1980, 2 of 3. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 1980, 3 of 3. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: 1981, 1 of 2. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: 1981, 2 of 2. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Life Booklet, ca. 1990. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Notes and Letters, 1957-1960. (Oversize-box 37, Oversize-folder 1, Half-box 37)
  - Notebook Yearbook, 1966 (1 of 2). (Oversize-box 37, Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Notebook Yearbook, 1966 (2 of 2) - Notes and Letters (removed from folder 1). (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 3, Oversize-box 37)
  - Misc. Papers, 1980s. (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 4, Oversize-box 37)
  - Spiritual Newsletters, 1986-1988. (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 5, Oversize-box 37)
  - Daily Writing, 1989. (Half-box 37)
  - Misc. Essays, 1989-1990. (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 7)
  - Special Letters, 1990s. (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 8)
  - "Current Book Materials", 1991. (Half-box 37, Oversize-folder 9)
  - Notebooks, 1986-1988. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1989. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1990. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 1991. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1992. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1993 (1 of 2). (Box 39, Folder 3, Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1993 (2 of 2). (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1994. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1996. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 1997 (1 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1997 (2 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 1998. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 1998-1999. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 1999. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 2000. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 2000. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 2001. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks, 2001-2002. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks, 2002. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks, 2005-2010. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Papers, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Resumes, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - "New York addresses", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - "Mondale" button and Medallion, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Whistle and Medallion, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1950s-1960s. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Special Film Correspondence: ca. 1960s, 1 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Special Film Correspondence: ca. 1960s, 2 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1960-1967. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence: 1960s-1970s, 1 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Correspondence: 1960s-1970s, 2 of 2. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1961-1963. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Baillie letter to Stanley Kubrick, 1964. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Personal and Misc. Correspondence, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Wilder Bentley Correspondence, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jack Stauffacher Correspondence, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Special Film Correspondence, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1968, 1 of 2. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1968, 1 of 2. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Misc. Correspondence, 1968. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1968-1969. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1969. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Letters, 1969-1970. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Special Film Correspondence, 1970s. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1971, 1 of 2. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1971, 2 of 2. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1971-1972, 1 of 2. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1971-1972, 2 of 2. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1971-1973. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1972, 1 of 3. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1972, 2 of 3. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1972, 3 of 3. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1972-1973. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1973, 1 of 3. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1973, 2 of 3. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1973, 3 of 3. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1974-1975. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1974-1977. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1976. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Silver Letters, 1976. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1977. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Correspondence: 1977-1978 (1 of 2). (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Correspondence: 1977-1978 (2 of 2). (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Letters and Notes, 1978-1979. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1979-1981. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Special Film Correspondence, ca. 1980s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1980-1981. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1981. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1982, 1 of 4. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1982, 2 of 4. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1982, 3 of 4. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1982, 4 of 4. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1983, 1 of 2. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1983, 2 of 2. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1983-1984. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1983-1988. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1984-1987. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1985, 1 of 3. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1985, 2 of 3. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1985, 3 of 3. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1985-1990. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1986. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1987, 1 of 4. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1987, 2 of 4. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1987, 3 of 4. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1987, 4 of 4. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca.1986-1987. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1988, 1 of 2. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence: ca. 1986-1988, 2 of 2. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1987. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1987-1988, 1 of 2. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1987-1988, 2 of 2. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1987-1997. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1988-1989. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Correspondence, ca. 1989-1990. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1989-1990, 1 of 2. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence: 1989-1990, 2 of 2. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Tully Correspondence, 1990s. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Special Film Correspondence, 1990s-2011. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Letters to George Lucas Foundation, 2008-2011. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Tulley Correspondence, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Miscellaneous Letters, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence, 2003. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence, 2005. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2006, 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2006, 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2007, 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2007, 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence, 2008. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2009, 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2009, 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2010, 1 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence: 2010, 2 of 2. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence, 2011. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Tulley and Baillie Postcards, ca. 1963-1986. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Postcards, 1971-1973. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Card Envelopes, 1977-1978. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Christmas Cards, 1977-1978. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Postcards, ca. 1977-1983. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Postcards, 1986-1987. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Baillie Postcards, 1987-1988. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Greeting Cards, 1987-1988. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Baillie Christmas Cards, 1988. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Card List, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Baillie Family Correspondence, ca. 1905. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950s. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1950s-1960s. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Tulley Correspondence, 1967-1971. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1967. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Letters and Notes, 1968. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1969. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1969. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Tulley Correspondence, ca. 1976. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1976-1984. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Correpondence, 1977-1979. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1982. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Baillie Correspondence, 1978-1986. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Tulley, Correspondence, 1985. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (1 of 2). (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (2 of 2). (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (1 of 2) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (2 of 2). (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Drawings, 1989-1990. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (1 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (2 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (3 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (1 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (2 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (3 of 3). (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Tulley Correspondence, 1991. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1995. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (1 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (2 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (3 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1997. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (1 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (2 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1997. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (1 of 3). (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (2 of 3). (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (3 of 3). (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1996. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Postcards, 1996-2001. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Letters, 1997-2001. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Correspondence, 1998-2001. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Syliva Sutherland Correspondence, 1999-2000. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (1 of 2). (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (2 of 2). (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2002. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2004. (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 2000-2001. (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Printed E-mails, 2000-2003. (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Navy Papers, 2000-2006. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Naval Sea Cadet Corps., 2001. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence, 2002-2006. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Correspondence, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Sylvia Sutherland drawings, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Correspondence, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, ca. 1990s. (Oversize-box 71, Folder 1)
- Series 3: Film Notes
  - Film Notes, 1956. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Film Catalog, 1959-1974. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Film Ideas, 1960s-1970s. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "A Day Ashore" script notes, 1962. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "To Parsifal" notes, 1963. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "To Parsifal" notes, ca. 1963 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - "Mass for the Dakota Sioux" notes, ca. 1963. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Feature Film notes, 1964. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Programs for Cinema Theater, 1964. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Film Society notes, ca. 1964. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - "Quixote" notes, 1964-1965. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Quixote Premier Flyers, 1964-1965. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Canyon Cinema Catalogue #1 and Cinema News, 1964-1966. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Film Programs, 1964-1988. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - "Work/2" book, 1965. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - European Film Festival Materials, 1965-1969. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Notes, 1966. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Termination" notes, 1966. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Baillie Retrospective Program Notes, 1966. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - "Castro Street"/"Tung" notes, 1966. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Three Short Pieces"/"All my Life"/"Still Life" notes, ca. 1966. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Film Making Manual notes, 1966-1967. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Canyon Cinema notes, 1966-1969. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - "A Day Ashore" notes, 1967. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - "Little Big Man" notes, 1967. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - "Martita" notes, ca. 1967. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - "Licho" notes, ca. 1967. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - "Tranformation/Going through some changes" notes, 1967. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Sogetsu Film Festival, 1967. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Notebooks on "Quick Billy", 1967-1969. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Quick Billy Notebook Summary, 1967-1970. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Film Society Newsletters, ca. 1967-1978. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Newsreels, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Canyon Cinema News, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - New Film notes, ca. 1968. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Sylvia Sutherland Poster, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - University of Cincinnati Festival Posters, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Film Festival Programs, ca. 1969. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Houston Working Notes, 1969-1970. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - "Quick Billy" Lab Records, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - "Quick Billy" Misc. Notes, ca. 1969-1970. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Canyon Cinema Cataloga and Flyers, 1969-1979. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - "Quick Billy" notes, 1969-1970. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - New Films, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "Quick Billy" matting projection notes, ca. 1970. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Baillie Film Comment, ca. 1970. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - "Fathar 2" Book, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Quick Billy Poster and Titles, ca. 1970. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Quick Billy Lab Sheets, ca. 1970. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - "Quick Billy" and "Mass" Synopses, ca. 1970. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - "Quixote" Notes, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Baillie Filmography and Personal Shows, ca. 1970s. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Film Notes and Misc. Writings, ca. 1971. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Baillie MOMA Retrospective, 1972. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - TV Ads/Media Notes, 1972. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "Roslyn Romance" notes, ca. 1972. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - "Quick Billy" notes, 1973. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - "Principles" notes, 1973. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Publications and Scripts, 1973. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Palmer Film Services, 1973. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Film Notes, ca. 1973. (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - "Roslyn Romance" Notes, ca. 1973. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - American Film Institute booklet, 1973. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Camera Price Lists and Catalogs, 1974. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - "Roslyn Romance (Is it really true?)" notes, 1974. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Sound notes, ca. 1974. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Future Feature notes, 1974-1975. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - "Roslyn Romance" Titles, ca. 1975. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous "Roslyn Romance" notes, 1975-1976. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Kids Films, 1976. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Dog Theater, 1976. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - "Roslyn Romance" timing notes, 1977. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - "Roslyn Romance" Video Version notes, 1978. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Film Notes, ca. 1980. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - "File III" notes, ca. 1980. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Film Ideas "to shoot and sound", 1981. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Cardinal Text Notes, 1982. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Reel IV "Light!" notes, 1982-1983. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Macrozoom Super 8 Film booklet, 1983. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Filmmaker's Co-op papers, 1988. (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - "Chapter XI" and "The Cairo Affair" notes, 2011-2012. (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Section Titles/"The Cardinals Visit", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Canyon Cinema News flyers, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Baillie Selected Papers/Canyon Cinema History, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Canyon Cinema News "Wanted" Posters, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Canyon Cinema, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - "Mr. Hayashi" notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - "Director" Score/Script, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Baillie Film Writing, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - "Italian Romance" notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Old Script Scores, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - "Morning Star" notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Early Canyon Cinema Notes, ca. 1962. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 1)
  - Carl Linder Posters, 1964. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 2)
  - Scott Bartlett Film Magazine, 1968. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 3)
  - "Quick Billy" notes, 1970. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 4)
  - "Quick Billy" working notes, 1970. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 5)
  - "Quick Billy" program notes, ca. 1970. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 6)
  - "Quick Billy" production notes: 1 of 5, ca. 1970. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 7)
  - "Quick Billy" production notes: 2 of 5, ca. 1970. (Oversize-box 34, Folder 8)